[This week, after a long absence (?), it's a two-parter.
The common theme is "?????"]
[We'll reveal the answer at the end of the show!]
So this is that place... The restaurant exclusively
for Amanto that recently opened.
ここか…
最近できたという➡
天人専門の料理屋…｡
[Beauty SHOCK Club]
[Note: Parody of Bishoku Club a Gourmet Club
from the Oishinbo manga.]
ああ 我ら地球人差別の
発信地となり➡
Yeah. It's where discrimination
against us Earthlings begins.
連日連夜 天人のVIPが
豪遊しているという話だ…｡
They say Amanto VIPs live
it up all day and all night.
Tsk...
ﾁｯ…｡
いくぞ｡
Let's go.
May I have your attention, everyone.
は～い 全員注目！
I'd like to introduce a new employee.
これから
新人を紹介するから➡
みんな 拍手で迎えてあげよう｡
Let's welcome him with
a round of applause.
拍手!!
(拍手)
Let's give him a hand!
じゃあ 自己紹介してくれ｡
Okay, introduce yourself, please.
(桂)どうも
ZURA78星雲からやってきました➡
How do you do? I come
from Nebula Zura78.
My name is Joey Katsura.
[Note: Parody of Joi, meaning
Anti-Foreigner Faction.]
ｼﾞｮｰｲ･ｶﾂｰﾗと申します｡
Please be good to me.
以後
よろしくお願いいたします｡
地球人じゃね？
Isn't he an Earthling?
["Japanese Restaurants Abroad Taste Pretty
Much like School Cafeteria Lunches"]
[No Earthlings Allowed!]
No need to be concerned, everyone.
みんな
心配しなくていいぞ｡
He's just a pitiful lad who's often mistaken
for an Earthling because of he looks.
彼はな こんな外見なんで➡
よく 地球人と間違えられる
かわいそうな子なんだ｡
そうだよな ｼﾞｮｲ君｡
(桂)ｼﾞｮｲじゃなく ｼﾞｮｰｲです｡
Isn't that right, Joi-kun?
It's not Joi, it's Joey.
But I'd rather you called me Katsura.
というより
ｶﾂｰﾗでお願いします｡
As you know, we don't allow Earthlings.
We serve only Amanto VIPs.
知ってのとおり
うちは 地球人の出入り禁止➡
天人の要人
御用達の店でな｡
舟盛りが名物だ｡
(桂)ｼｭｰﾙですね｡
Our specialty is sashimi on a boat.
How surreal.
なんか言った？
Did you say something?
Anyway, we have a reservation
today by high-ranking VIPs
とにかく 今日も
超VIPのどっかの星の➡
from a royal family of
a planet somewhere.
王族様の予約が
入ってるから➡
初日から しっかりやってもらうぞ
ｼﾞｮｲ君｡
I'll need you to work hard on
your first day, Joi-kun.
No, please call me Katsura.
だから
ｶﾂｰﾗでお願いします｡
((桂さん!! 例の店の店員に
なりすますなんて 本気ですか!?
Katsura-san!
Are you serious about posing as
an employee at that restaurant?!
ｳﾜｻじゃ あの店には
過激派の連中が➡
Rumor has it that radicals are
targeting Amanto bigwigs
天人の要人 狙って
店もろとも闇討ちするって！
at that restaurant and they're planning
to blow it up with the Amanto inside!
一人で行くなんて
ﾑﾁｬです！
危険すぎだ！
It's reckless to go in there alone!
It's too dangerous!
Don't worry. It's easier if I work alone.
案ずるな
一人のほうが動きやすい｡
I will put that restaurant out of business
and force it to close for sure...
必ず あの店を
閉店に追い込み➡
営業できぬよう
仕向けてみせる｡
今回に関しては
過激派の連中の気持も➡
In this case, I can understand
how the radicals feel.
わからんではない｡
But if they get violent, there'll
be needless casualties.
しかし 派手にやっては
無用な犠牲者がでる｡
That's why, what I need to do
is make the Amanto leave
(桂)だからこそ
ﾔﾂらが ﾑﾁｬをする前に➡
ｵﾚが 天人どもを
立ち去らせればよいのだ｡
before the radicals do anything stupid.
(一同)桂さん！ 桂さん！))
Katsura-san!
That's reckless!
Come back!
[Be careful.]
あっ じゃあｶﾂｰﾗ君｡
Got that, Katsura-kun?
I'm going to introduce you to your
Senpai who'll oversee you.
ｷﾐが 直接つく
先輩 紹介するから｡
You, step forward.
おい 前来て｡
(ﾊﾀ皇子)くるしゅうないぞ｡
As you were.
This is Hata-koh. Although he
joined us just a week ago,
ｺｲﾂは ﾊﾀ公だ｡
先週 入ったばかりだけど
一応 ｷﾐの先輩になるから➡
he's still your Senpai, so ask him
anything you need to know.
いろいろ 聞いてくれ｡
(桂)あの どこかで
お会いしましたか？
Um...Have we met before?
I don't remember anyone like you.
お主のようなのは
見覚えないがの｡
He's to be pitied, as well.
実は ｺｲﾂも
かわいそうでﾔﾂでな｡
なんか 自分のｺﾚｸｼｮﾝと
一緒に間違われて➡
Seems he was mistaken as part of his own
collection and discarded along with them.
捨てられちまったらしいんだよ｡
Let's see...we don't want
anything in this room.
((えっと この部屋にあるﾔﾂ
全部いらねえから｡
Take them all away before
that idiot returns.
ﾊﾞｶが帰ってくる前に
全部 持っていってくれや｡
If you see anything that might
be of worth, leave it here.
(じい)もし 金に
なりそうなのあったら➡
置いといてくれ
他は全部 廃棄で))
Throw everything else out.
Damn old coot!
あのじじい！
Anyway, he'll look after
you. Try to get along.
とりあえず ｷﾐの面倒
全部 みてもらうから｡
仲よくやってくれ｡
That's right. Ask me anything.
そうじゃ 余に
何でも聞くのじゃぞ➡
Joy Toy, was it?
ｼﾞｮｲﾄｲとやら｡
ｼﾞｮｲﾄｲじゃないです｡
It's not Joy Toy. It's Joey Katsura.
I can't do an S split.
[Note: Parody of Yinling of Joytoym, a swimsuit model
known for her leg spread pose that looks like an M.]
ｼﾞｮｰｲ･ｶﾂｰﾗです
Ｓ字開脚とかできません｡
No, he's not an S, he's
an M. He can't do S.
[Note: S&M refers to sadism/masochism]
いやそれ ＳじゃなくてＭだから｡
Ｓは 絶対ﾑﾘ｡
Yeah...
あぁ 心配するな｡
Don't worry.
But what if...
[無線]しかし 万が一｡
(桂)案ずるなと言っただろう｡
I said don't worry.
All I need to do is to set this bomb
to go off after the restaurant closes.
(桂)あとは 閉店後に
爆発するよう➡
この爆弾をｾｯﾄするだけだ｡
それで しばらくは
営業できまい｡
That'll put them out of
business for a while.
Hey, newcomer. What're you
doing? Give me a hand.
おい 新人なにやっとる
手伝わんか｡
いや Ｓ字開脚の練習を…｡
(ﾊﾀ)あ できた…｡
I was practicing my S split.
...Oh, you did it.
Done.
ぎょ…｡
おぉ！ 見事な船長だ｡
That's a lovely sea captain.
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊ 何でもこうたるて｡
ﾎﾝﾄ？
I'll buy you anything you want.
Really?
いらっしゃいませ｡
いいよ｡
Welcome.
Stop.
Go and clean the windows
or something, newcomer.
新人は 窓でも拭いててくれ｡
しかし…｡
But...
まぁ 見てりゃわかるさ｡
Watch and learn.
Hey, Earthling.
おい 地球人｡
This is no place for scum like you.
ここは ｵﾒｴらのような ｸｽﾞどもが
来る場所じゃねえんだよ！
ｷｬｰ！
Tch, I'm not sitting with apes like them.
ｹｯ！ あんなｻﾙどもと
同じ席につけるかよ｡
Just having Earthlings in the
vicinity ruins my appetite.
地球人が入っただけで
ﾒｼがまずくなるぜ！
Apes should eat ape food.
ｻﾙには ｻﾙの
ｴｻってもんがあんだろうがよ！
ｷﾞｬｰ！ 目が!!
My eyes!
Hey! What're you doing
to the customer?!
おい！ 客に
何やってんの!!
目は心の窓といいますからな｡
うまくねえんだよ！
You know, they say the eyes
are the window to the soul.
Not his eyes!
And you, Hata-koh! What're
you teaching him?!
つうか ﾊﾀ公！
お前 なに教えてんの！
Joey! How useless can
you be?! Do as I do!
ｼﾞｮｰｲ！ お前は
どこまで使えないんじゃ！
余のやるとおりにするのじゃ！
あ 拭き拭き…｡
ｵﾒｴは どこ拭いてんだよ!!
Where are you wiping?!
ﾁｬｯｸは 社会の窓というからの｡
うるせえ！
They say the zipper is the
window to the world.
Shut up!
Huh?
I-It...came off? Y-You...are an Earthling?
と とれた!?
お お前… もしかして地球人!?
Oh, come on. Look
how easily
this comes off. See?
いやだなぁ こんなの
簡単にとれますよ｡
ほら｡
(ﾊﾀ)ｷﾞｬｰ！
You guys! Quit horsing around
and get back to work!
お前ら もういいから
裏で作業してろ！
Why am I stuck doing this sort of work?
なんで余が こんなことしないと
ならんのじゃ｡
《やはり この店…➡
Just as I thought, this restaurant is an ugly
place where they make fun of Earthlings.
我々 地球人をｺｹにする
ひどい場所であったか…｡
I'll revert to the original plan, and...
ならば 当初の計画どおり…》
Hey newcomer, what're you doing?
おい 新人｡ 何をしておる？
いや… 小腹が空いたので➡
I got a little hungry, so I was looking
for something to snack on...
何か つまみ食いできるものは
ないかと…｡
I found dried squid, see?
あっ… ｽﾙﾒ 見つけましたよ｡
ほら｡
それ 余の ﾁｬｰﾑﾎﾟｲﾝﾄ～!!
That's my charm point!
(桂)ところで 先輩｡
Just curious, Senpai...
なんで こんな店で
ずっと 働いてるんですか？
Why are you working at a place like this?
You said you were discarded
by mistake, right?
先輩は 間違って
捨てられただけなんですよね？
家に 戻れば…｡
Why not go home?
う～ん…
ここには ｼﾞｮﾝがおるからな～｡
Well...because John is here.
…ｼﾞｮﾝ？
...John?
(ﾊﾀ)うん｡ 店の生け簀におる
宇宙伊勢海老の ｼﾞｮﾝじゃ｡
Yes. John, the space lobster who
lives in the restaurant's fish tank.
He's a lovable sort. I fell in love
with him the moment I saw him.
ういﾔﾂでの～！ 出会った
そのときに ﾌｫｰﾘﾝﾗﾌﾞじゃ！
If I'm not careful, there's no telling
when John might get eaten.
油断しとると
ｼﾞｮﾝが いつ食われてしまうか➡
わからんからの～｡ 余が
離れるわけには いかんのじゃ｡
I can't leave him.
If everyone believed in "love and peace"
and loved animals like I do,
皆が 余のように➡
生き物を愛する
ﾗﾌﾞ＆ﾋﾟｰｽの心をもっていれば➡
すべて うまくいくのにの～｡
everything would be fine.
Well, I'm worried about John,
so I'll go back first.
じゃあ 余はｼﾞｮﾝが気になるので
先に戻っているぞ｡
Love and peace, eh?
ﾗﾌﾞ＆ﾋﾟｰｽ… か…｡
《これを 爆発させれば➡
If I detonate this, the tank
and John won't survive.
生け簀もｼﾞｮﾝも
ただでは 済むまい…｡
小さき命だろうが
犠牲を出すようでは➡
It's a tiny life, but if there are casualties,
then I'm no different than the radicals.
過激派の連中と 変わりはない…｡
ｵﾚは ｵﾚのやり方で
大志を遂げる！》
I will use my own methods...
...to accomplish my ambition.
(悲鳴)
Wh-Who are you?!
な… なんだ!? ｷｻﾏら！
This is divine retribution!
天誅で ござる！
We've come to pass judgment
on the likes of you who
ｷｻﾏらのような 地球人を差別し➡
この国を蝕み 滅ぼす連中は
我々が裁きを下す！
discriminate against Earthlings and
undermine and ruin our country!
あの世にて 懺悔するがいい!!
Go repent in hell!
へっ！ 攘夷志士か｡
こんなことも あろうかと…➡
Hmph. Anti-Foreigner Faction samurai,
eh? I figured as much.
準備は万全だ！
I'm ready for you.
♪♪～
《まずいぞ…
なんじゃ!? これは!?
Uh-oh...what's going on? If these
guys start fighting here...
こんな所で
ｺｲﾂら暴れ出しよったら➡
the tank...
生け簀が… 余のｼﾞｮﾝが…！》
and my John...
《しまった！ 過激派の連中が
もう 来るとは…！》
Darn! I didn't think the radicals
would show up so soon.
Stop it!
(ﾊﾀ)やめるんじゃ～!!
許さんぞ～!!
人の心をもたぬ 愚か者どもめ！
I won't allow this! You're all
fools with no compassion!
誰も 傷つけては ならんぞ！
You mustn't injure him!
Don't put a single scratch
on his precious shell!
大切な命に
傷ひとつ つけてみよ!!
余が… 余が…！
If you do, I'll...I'll...
余が許さ～ん!!
I won't forgive you!
ﾁｯ！ お前ら天人が 命を語るか!!
Are you talking about Amanto lives?!
まずは
ｷｻﾏから 成敗してくれるわ～!!
Then I'll start by...
killing you first!
うわぁ～っ!!
なっ…!?
ｷﾞｮ！
ﾊﾀ？
What?!
Huh?
もう… 誰も 血を流すんじゃない｡
...No more...no more bloodshed...let
there be...
そう…➡
ﾗﾌﾞ＆ﾋﾟｰｽだ!!
Love and peace!
か… 桂!!
ち… 地球人だったのか！
Ka-Katsura!
S-So he was an Earthling?
生きとし生けるものを…➡
We are all living creatures...
誰かを
安易に傷つけるようなことでは➡
Doing harm to any of them
will not solve a thing.
何も 解決せんのだ！
ｵﾚは 今日
ようやくそれを学んだ｡
I finally learned that today. Yes...
そう… この 先輩からな｡
From Senpai here...
ｶﾂｰﾗ…｡
...Katsura...
(桂)先輩…｡
Senpai...
♪♪～
くぉら～!!
Dammit! I paid good money to eat here!
What's the meaning of this commotion?!
お前ら～！ 人が 高い金払って
ﾒｼ食ってるときに➡
なに騒いでやがる!!
I was having a great time after finally
こちとら ようやく捨てちまった
ﾊﾞｶの替え玉も 見つかって➡
気分よくやってんのによ～！
finding a replacement for
the idiot I disposed of!
ねぇ～！ 新皇子～！
(ﾆｾ皇子)ｺｯﾊｧｰｯ！
Isn't that right, my new Prince?
You see! The Prince is angry!
ほら！
皇子も 怒ってんだろうが!!
…あれ？
...Huh?
ｺｯﾊｧｰｯ！
That's odd...there are two Princes.
おかしいな… 皇子が ２人…｡
ふざけんな～!!
ぐはっ…!!
Cut it out!
ﾃﾒｴ!! ぶっ殺したる～!!
Damn you...I'll kill you! Enough of this!
I'm gonna pound you to death!
おら～っ!!
いいかげんにせいよ ｺﾗ～!!
(桂)どいて！
Out of my way.
[Note: Katsura is talking like a mother.]
そんなんだったら！
If that's how it is, then you guys
can do whatever you want!
ｱﾝﾀたちの好きに
すればいいじゃないの!! もう～!!
I've had it!
《一同:お母さん？》
Mother?
(長谷川)いや～
ここまで 長かったよ～｡
I must say it took a long
time to get to this point.
(長谷川)親方のところに
弟子入りしてから➡
Since joining this shop as an apprentice,
包丁を 握らせてもらえない
下働きの生活｡
Chef wouldn't let me handle a knife, so
I worked the menial jobs in the kitchen.
Everyday, I diligently watched the Chef as he
made sushi so I could figure out his technique.
(長谷川)毎日 寿司を握る
親方の手もとを盗み見ては➡
ｼｬﾘの握り方の練習をしてよう｡
And I practiced his technique
for forming the rice.
(長谷川)ようやく この支店を
預からせてもらえるようになった｡
Now finally, he's entrusted me
with a branch restaurant.
This time, I'm going to succeed.
(長谷川)
今度こそやるよ ｵﾚは～!!
Good for you, Chef Hasegawa!
(お妙)よっ！ 長谷川店長！
Stop it, you're embarrassing me!
よせやい！ 照れるべ～！
(お登勢)やっぱり 男は
手に職つけないとね～｡
A man should have a trade.
Your wife who ran out on you
might come back now, eh?
これで 逃げた嫁さんも
帰ってくるんじゃないかい？
You've worked hard.
よくがんばったね ｱﾝﾀ！
Today, I want all of you
who supported me
(長谷川)今日は
応援してくれたみんなに➡
ｵﾚの握った寿司
最初に食べてほしくてよ！
to be the first ones to try
the sushi I've made.
全部 ｵﾚの おごりだ！
好きなだけ食べてってくれ！
Everything is on the house.
Eat all you want!
(神楽)ｷｬｯﾎ～!!
寿司なんて 久しぶりね！
I haven't had sushi in ages!
What shall I have?
なに 食べようかな～！
(お妙)あっ！ 流れてきたわ！
Here it comes.
(お妙)
まぁ おいしそうな ｶｯﾊﾟ巻き！
My, how delicious the
cucumber rolls look!
(お妙)神楽ちゃん！
一緒に食べよっか｡
Shall we share some, Kagura-chan?
Sure.
(新八)おっ 次もｶｯﾊﾟ巻き｡
The next one is also a cucumber roll.
You're good at cucumber
rolls, Hasegawa-san.
長谷川さん
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻き 得意なんですね｡
I think that's what I'll have.
じゃあ これﾎﾞｸいただきます｡
(銀時)またか
まぁ最初はｶｯﾊﾟ巻くらいが
...Another one.
Oh well, cucumber rolls might be a good
way to get the stomach started.
腹をならすのに いいのかも…｡
沙悟浄か！ ｵﾚたちは!!
What do you think we are, vegetarians?!
There are cucumber rolls
from here to Gandhara!
[Note: Gandhara is a location from the
Journey to the West Chinese novel.]
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻きが
ｶﾞﾝﾀﾞｰﾗまで続いてんだろうが！
Why're you being so stingy?
Bring out the fatty tuna!
何 ｹﾁってるんだよ ｺﾞﾗ～！
ﾄﾛ出せ ｳﾆ出せ!!
Bring out the sea urchin!
何のために 貴重な時間割いて
ﾃﾒｴみたいなﾓﾝに➡
Why do you think we
took precious time off
to come and see someone like you?!
会いに来たと思ってんだ！
I can't make anything but cucumber rolls.
(長谷川)ｶｯﾊﾟしか握れねえんだよ！
The truth is, I don't know
how to make sushi yet.
ｵﾚ 本当は
まだ寿司なんか握れねえんだよ！
["Once You've Taken a Dish, You Can't Put it Back"]
[Edo Style Sushi-go-Round Kabukicho branch]
So you're telling us that the story
(お登勢)するってえと何か？
about the Chef recognizing
your abilities was a lie...
親方に認められたってのはｳｿで
実は 親方は入院して➡
and the truth is the Chef is in the hospital
and unable to come to the restaurant,
店に出られなくなり
急遽 ﾊﾞｲﾄのｱﾝﾀに店を任せたと｡
so he hired you, a part-timer, and
left you in charge of the place?
(長谷川)この ｽｼﾏｼｰﾝがあるから
大丈夫だって聞いたんだが➡
He said everything would be fine because
there was this sushi machine,
ｺｲﾂがｳﾝともｽﾝとも いわなくてよ｡
but it won't do a darned thing.
もうすぐ 開店の時間だってのに
どうすりゃいいんだ？
It's almost time to open for business-
what should I do?
こんなんじゃ ここは
｢まるでﾀﾞﾒなお寿司屋｣➡
This place will become the "completely
hopeless sushi restaurant" Madao!
ﾏﾀﾞｵに なりさがっちまう！
Right now, all we can do is
repair the sushi machine.
とりあず そのｽｼﾏｼｰﾝとやらを➡
修理するしか
ないんじゃないかい？
Take a look at it, Tama.
たま ちょっと見ておやりよ｡
(たま)了解しました｡
Understood.
(長谷川)おっ なんだ!?
What's that?
Tama can communicate with machines
(お登勢)たまはね
ｶﾗｸﾘと対話して 故障原因を探り➡
and can find the cause of the
problem so we can fix it.
修理することができるのさ｡
飲む？ 横 いいかな？
[Canned oil]
Want some? Mind if I stand
here next to you?
どうしたの？ ﾌﾞﾙｰ入ってんじゃん
ひょっとして まだ➡
What's the matter? You look blue.
[Note: Parody of common soap opera
themes among office workers.]
Could it be you're still bothered by
the microwave oven manager?
電子ﾚﾝｼﾞ課長のこと
引きずってるの？
すごいよ 完全に
OLの昼休みの風景だよ｡
Awesome. This is totally the scene
between two female office workers.
電子ﾚﾝｼﾞ課長って誰だよ｡
Who's the microwave oven manager?
I told you to forget about him.
やめなって言ったじゃん
あの人…➡
That guy...has no intention
of leaving his wife.
奥さんと別れるつもりないよ
あの人 あなただけじゃない➡
You're not the only one.
庶務課のﾚｼﾞ子も ﾁﾝしてんのよ｡
He nuked Rejiko in
general affairs as well.
[Note: Rejiko means cash register.]
They're having quite an
involved discussion.
えらく 込み入った話に
なってるんですけど｡
甘ったれてるんじゃないわよ！
Stop acting like a child!
負けんな！
Don't give up.
Be strong!
強くなりな！
東京に… 自分に負けんな！
Don't let Tokyo-or yourself-
get you down!
手は尽くしましたが
修正不可能のようです｡
I did all I could, but it appears unfixable.
You completely destroyed it just now!
完全に お前が壊したよね 今
とどめ さしたよね！
You finished it off.
Hey, what're you going to do about this?
ｵｲｯ どうしてくれるんだ！
唯一の希望を!!
That was my only hope!
There's no time left.
もう 時間ねえってのに！
I'm starving.
お腹 へったな！
うん！
いらっしゃいませ！
とにかく ｶｳﾝﾀｰは➡
W-Welcome.
Catherine and I will man the counter.
私と ｷｬｻﾘﾝが何とかするから
ｱﾝﾀら 裏方でﾌｫﾛｰしな！
You follow our lead and take
care of things in back.
G-Gotcha!
わ わかった！
Th-Thank you, everyone for
helping me out with this.
す すまねえ みんな！
こんなこと 手伝わせることに
なっちまって…｡
Don't worry, Hasegawa-san.
大丈夫ですよ 長谷川さん
困ったときは➡
When we need help, we help each
other out, right? Leave it to us.
お互い 助け合いでしょう
ﾎﾞｸらに任せてください｡
しかし ｵﾚ以上に
素人の お前たちに➡
But you have less experience
with sushi than I do-
寿司なんて 握れるわけねえよ！
there's no way you can make sushi.
回転寿司に 誰もそこまで
完成度 求めてねえよ！
No one expects perfection at a
conveyor belt sushi restaurant.
上にﾈﾀがのって
形さえ取り繕ってりゃ➡
As long as there's a topping on top of a decently
formed rice ball, we'll be able to fool them.
なんとか ごまかせるはずだ｡
Hasegawa-san, at the very least,
長谷川さん すみませんけど
最低限だけでも➡
would you mind teaching
us how to form the rice?
ｼｬﾘの握り方 教えてもらえます？
Even if you know how to make
only cucumber rolls,
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻きしか作れないといっても
形だけは 親方さんの見て➡
you did watch Chef make them, so
you know how it's done, right?
知ってらっしゃるんですよね｡
All right. It was monkey see, monkey
do, but watch closely.
わかった！ 見よう 見まねだが
よく見ててくれ｡
First, you take the rice.
まず ｼｬﾘをとる｡
このとき あまり
取りすぎないように➡
Be careful not to take too much.
気をつけてくれ
強すぎず 弱すぎない加減で➡
Squeeze the rice not too
hard, and not too soft,
片手で空気を含むように握るんだ｡
with one hand so that
air gets into the rice.
ﾜｻﾋﾞをつけ ﾈﾀをのせる ひと握り｡
Put on the wasabi, then the
topping. And the sushi....
完成だ！
なんでだよ！
is done.
What the?!
How did that end up turning
into a cucumber roll?!
なんで あそこから
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻きが完成するんですか！
今 ｶｯﾄをまたぐ間に
何があったんだよ!!
Something happened when
we switched scenes!
(長谷川)うぅ… ﾀﾞﾒだ…
ｵﾚ やっぱりｶｯﾊﾟ巻きしか作れねえ｡
It's hopeless. I can only
make cucumber rolls.
今 惜しいとこまでいったじゃん！
ﾏｸﾞﾛのせてたじゃん!!
You were so close just now.
You placed a slice of tuna on top.
なんで ｷｭｳﾘに変わってるの！
How'd that change into a cucumber roll?!
[Note: The literal translation for cucumber
roll is "water imp roll."]
He must be cursed because his
ancestors killed a water imp.
先祖が ｶｯﾊﾟ殺したりとか
呪われてんだよ｡
いっぺん 死んでみる？
ﾀﾞﾒだ…｡
He is hopeless.
This won't do. We'll just put Hasegawa-san
in charge of cucumber rolls.
長谷川さんは
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻き要員にしましょう｡
でも 雰囲気だけは伝わったわ
形だけなら私➡
I think I got the general idea.
I feel I can at least make something
that looks like sushi.
なんとか
できそうな気がしてきた！
I agree. There's no heat involved, so
I'm sure even you could do it, Sis.
そうですね 火も使わないし➡
これなら 姉上でも大丈夫ですよ
きっと｡
空気を含むように握り
ﾜｻﾋﾞをつける｡
Shape it so air gets into the
grains and add the wasabi.
ﾈﾀを乗せて ひと握り
やったわ できた！
Place the topping, and give it
a squeeze. I did it. It's done.
What is that?!
だから なんでだよ～！
Why is it burned to a crisp?!
なんで 丸こげに
なってるんですか！
When did you add heat?
What did you just do?
いつ 火入れた なにした 今！
Actually, I've been a bit feverish
since yesterday.
実は 昨日から私
ちょっと 熱っぽいのよね｡
How hot are you?! Go home!
どんだけ発熱してるんだ！ 帰れ!!
すぐ病院に行ってください！
頭の!!
Go to the hospital immediately!
For your lousy head!
ﾃﾒｴら 素人のくせに
ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬ考えてっから➡
You guys fail because you don't know
what you're doing and
you think too much.
失敗するんだろうが！
そんな職人技 いらねえ｡
You don't need masterful skill.
ｵﾚたちゃ まずくても
形さえ繕えば いいんだよ ﾎﾗ｡
All we have to do is get the shape
right, even if it tastes bad.
See?
形を守れ！ これ もう寿司ですら
なくなってんだろうが!!
You get the shape right!
This isn't even sushi anymore!
文句を言う前に
まず 食べてみてください｡
Taste it before you complain. Will
you be able to, once you do?
同じ口が きけますかね｡
食べねえよ！
I won't eat it! It has the look of
an entry in a pastry contest!
なに ﾊﾟﾃｨｼｴ試験みてえな感じ
かもし出してんだよ！
(お妙)じゃあ 銀さんのﾊﾟﾌｪと
私の焼きおにぎりは➡
All right, we'll put Gin-san's parfait and
my toasted rice ball on the side menu.
ｻｲﾄﾞﾒﾆｭｰに回しましょう｡
焼きおにぎりじゃねえだろ ｺﾚ！
That's not a toasted rice
ball. It's a burnt corpse.
焼死体だろ ｺﾚ！ 痛っ!!
Ow!
あら 神楽ちゃん
なに やってるの!?
Kagura-chan, what're you doing?
ん～ どうあるか これ｡
What do you think of this?
Ohhh! Now this...
おぉ… ちょっ これ…｡
(お妙)すごいわ 神楽ちゃん！
That's awesome, Kagura-chan!
It's a perfect piece of sushi!
完璧だわ！ 寿司よ!!
これ どこからどう見ても 寿司よ｡
It's sushi no matter how you look at it!
これだったら 店に出しても
大丈夫じゃない？
This would be all right to serve in
the restaurant, don't you think?
いや でけえだろ！
つうか こんなでっけえ➡
No, it's too big.
Where did you get a slice
of tuna this huge?!
ﾏｸﾞﾛの切り身
どっから持ってきたんだよ！
夢だったある でかい寿司に
かぶりつくのが…｡
It's been my dream to
bite into a huge sushi.
You're not supposed to
make it for yourself.
お前のために作ってんじゃねえよ
こんなもん 食えるﾔﾂ➡
Where in the world are you going to
find someone who can eat this?!
どこの世界にいるんだよ！
We have an order for
egg roll and shrimp!
(お登勢)卵と海老 入りました！
What're we going to do?
どうするんですか？ まだ寿司
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻きしか できていませんよ｡
We still don't have any finished
sushi except cucumber rolls.
Let me handle this.
(たま)私に お任せください｡
たまさん！
寿司のﾃﾞｰﾀは おおよそとれました｡
Tama-san!
I have sufficient data on sushi.
(たま)材料を
用意していただけますか？
Would you please ready the ingredients?
(２人)うわっ…！
She ate it?!
食べた!?
No.
いや…｡
Sh...She's...!
(２人)こ… これは!?
ｵｴｪｪｪ… ｵｴｯ…｡
できました｡
(長谷川)食えるか!!
Done.
We can't serve that!
How gross can you get?! Are you King
Piccolo?! That's mostly vomit!
[Note: Refers to a Dragonball character.]
どんだけ ｸﾞﾛﾃｽｸな
作り方してんだ お前は!!
ﾋﾟｯｺﾛ大魔王か!?
ほとんど ｹﾞﾛじゃねえか！
(たま)からくりは
ｹﾞﾛなど吐きません！
A robot does not vomit. I simply prepared
the sushi inside my body.
体の中で
寿司を調理しただけです｡
なんか ﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛしたの
ついてるだろうが！
There's something gooey all over it!
ｵｲﾙです｡
もう 四の五の言ってる➡
That's oil.
This is no time for talk.
場合じゃねえよ｡
作り方はどうあれ➡
Regardless of how it was made,
this looks the most decent.
見た目は いちばんﾏｼだ｡
めんどくせえから回すぞ｡
I'll save you the trouble-
I'm putting it out.
ちょっと～!! 待って～ ああっ!!
Just a minute!
Wait!
♪♪～
Delicious!
[Note: Customers are parodies of Kaibara Yuzan
and Yamaoka Shiro of Oshinbo manga.]
うまい!!
なんだ？ この新食感！
What is this new texture? It has a
flavor I've never tasted before!
今まで食べたことのない味だ！
まったりとしていて
それでいて しつこくない！
Thick and smooth, yet not overpowering!
What is this?!
なんだ これは!?
(２人)寿司の革命だ!!
It's a revolutionary new sushi!
おい！
ｵﾚにも ｿｲﾂと同じやつ頼む！
Hey! I want the same thing!
Me, too!
ｵﾚも！
ﾜｲも！
ｱﾁｷも！
Same here!
The same!
奇跡だ… 奇跡が起こった｡
It's a miracle. A miracle happened.
いける！ これはいける!!
We can do this! This is going to work!
吐かせろ！ ｼﾞｬﾝｼﾞｬﾝ食わせて
ｹﾞﾛｹﾞﾛ 吐かせ続けるんだ！
Keep her spitting them out!
Keep her fed and keep
her spitting them out!
店にある食材
すべて持ってこ～い!!
Bring all the ingredients we
have in the restaurant!
(神楽)すご～い！ 飛ぶように
皿が さばけていくｱﾙ！
This is incredible! The plates
are flying off the line!
店の前も 長蛇の列です！
There's a long line out front, too!
きた～！ これきた～!!
We did it! We've done it!
長谷川さん あまりの客足に
材料がつきかけてるわ！
Hasegawa-san! With so many customers,
we're running low on ingredients.
What?!
なっ なに!?
ﾁｷｼｮｳ！
立身出世の この絶好のﾁｬﾝｽに➡
Dammit. This was my
chance to make it big.
ｵﾚってやつは
どこまでﾏﾀﾞｵなんだ！
How much of a Madao can I be?!
行けよ｡
Go.
ｱﾝﾀは なんとしても
材料をかき集めてこい｡
You go and do whatever it takes
to gather up ingredients.
それまで ｵﾚたちが
この場を持たしてみせる｡
We'll hold down the fort
here until you get back.
早く行け！
Hurry and go!
頼んだぜ!!
I'm counting on you!
Toshi, what's with this place?
(近藤)ﾄｼ なんだ？ ここは…｡
回転寿司と聞いて来てみれば…➡
I came because I heard this was a conveyor
belt sushi restaurant, but...
回転してるのは
ｶｯﾊﾟ巻きばかりではないか｡
the only things on the belt
are cucumber rolls.
(土方)隊士どもの話じゃ
安くてうまいと➡
The guys said this place was cheap
and delicious. Was it bull?
評判だったんだが ｶﾞｾだったかね｡
(土方)店員の態度は最悪だし…｡
The attitude of the staff is the worst.
What's with them? I'm
going to tell them off.
何だ？ あれ
ｶﾞﾂﾝと言ってくるかな ｵﾚ…｡
(近藤)やめろ ﾄｼ
ﾒｼくらい おだやかに食わせろ！
Don't, Toshi. Let's eat our meal quietly.
なんだ？
あの溶けた ﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛのﾊﾟﾌｪ…｡
What's with that melting parfait?
Why're they sending it around?
なんで回転させてんだ？
冷やしとけよ｡
Keep it chilled.
(近藤)おい ﾄｼ！ あれ 何だ？
Hey, Toshi, what's that?
Could that be dark matter?
あれ ひょっとして
ﾀﾞｰｸﾏﾀｰじゃねえか？
(土方)なんで ﾀﾞｰｸﾏﾀｰが ｶｯﾊﾟ巻きと
一緒に回転してんだよ？
Why would dark matter be spinning on
the belt alongside cucumber rolls?
300円だぞ おい どうする？
買っとくか？ ﾄｼ！
It's 300 yen. What should I do?
Should I take it, Toshi?
ﾀﾞｰｸﾏﾀｰより ｵﾚが頼んだ
ｶﾚｲのｴﾝｶﾞﾜは いつ来るんだよ？
Never mind the dark matter.
When's the flatfish filet sushi
I ordered going to show up?
[Flat Curry]
(近藤)何だ？ 今の…｡
What was that just now?
What's curry doing in a sushi shop?
(土方)なんで寿司屋に
ｶﾚｰが回ってるんだ？
なんか 縁側のｶﾚｰ
って書いてなかった？
Didn't it have "flat curry" written on it?
Toshi, maybe that's your order.
ﾄｼ あれ… ひょっとして
お前が頼んだ…｡
いや 違うだろ
ｵﾚが頼んだのは ｶﾚｲのｴﾝｶﾞﾜだ｡
No, it's not. What I ordered
was flatfish filet.
いや そうなんだが…｡
Well, yeah, but...
[Flat Curry Filet]
(近藤)ﾄｼ… 一周回ったら
微妙に近寄ってきてるんだが…｡
Toshi, after one cycle, it's
getting a little closer.
いや 違う違う｡
ｵﾚのは ｶﾚｲのｴﾝｶﾞﾜだからね｡
No, it's not. I ordered flatfish filet.
[Flat Curry Filet on Flat Board]
おい 無理やり
ｶﾚｰの縁側に収まっちまったぞ｡
Hey, it's gotten to "flat curry
filet on flat board."
これ 完全にお前のだよ！
ｶﾚｰじゃねえ｡
This has to be yours.
I didn't order curry, I ordered flatfish.
ｶﾚｲだっつってんだろ！
[Hurry up and take the curry, stupid.]
Who're they calling stupid, dammit?!
誰がﾊﾞｶだ この野郎!!
おい 完全に ﾒｯｾｰｼﾞになってるよ｡
Hey, it's totally sending you a message.
Hmph. I'm not taking it.
ﾌﾝ！ 誰が取るか｡
なんで 寿司屋で
ｶﾚｰ食わなきゃいけねえんだ？
Why do I have to eat curry
at a sushi restaurant?
それより ｵﾚのｲｶは まだか？
一向に見えんのだが…｡
Anyway, what's keeping my ika?
I haven't seen it at all.
[Note: "Ika" means squid.]
おい… あれ
三代目 ｲｶ蔵じゃねえのか？
Hey, wasn't that Ikazo Sandaime? Could that
be your order, Kondo-san?
ひょっとして 近藤さんの…｡
いや違う｡ ｵﾚが頼んだのは ｲｶだ｡
三代目 ｲｶ蔵じゃねえ！
No, it's not. I ordered ika, not Ikazo Sandaime.
(土方)いや… でも ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ
こっち見てんだけど｡
Maybe not, but he's giving you the eye.
(近藤)違う！ 目 合わせんな！
No. Don't look at him!
He's stuck. Ikazo's stuck.
(土方)あっ 挟まった｡
ｲｶ蔵 挟まった｡
挟まったけど まだ こっち見てる｡
ｲｶ蔵 こっち見てる！
He's stuck but he's still looking this way.
Ikazo's looking this way!
何なんだ？ この店…｡
What's with this place?
Let's go home. This is creepy.
おい もう帰ろうぜ！
気持悪いよ｡
(土方)わけわかんね…｡
うわぁ！
I don't get this place.
(近藤)おい～！
ｲｶ蔵 ｶﾚｰ持ってきた～!!
Hey! Ikazo's bringing curry!
(土方)両方 無理やり
受け取らせるつもりだ～!!
He intends to force us to eat both of them!
(近藤/土方)ｷﾞｬｰｯ!!
♪♪～
Stop!
(３人)ｵﾚ 知～らね!!
Isn't it delicious?
うおぉぉぉ～!!
待ってろ みんな！
今すぐに行く～!!
Wait for me, everyone! I'll be there soon!
[Preview]
Can I do it, Senpai?
Cattle abduction? Sure, go ahead.
Hey! Give me back my analog stick!
The next episode... "Novices Only
Need a Flathead and a Phillips."
[Beings from the planet Gamer arrive at summer's end.
The Odd Jobs are modified one after another!]
[What? What were the hidden words?
The common theme was "giving up."]